<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Practice in Code</title>
<link>https://tlint101.github.io/practice-in-code/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://tlint101.github.io/practice-in-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Practice in Code</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 16:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Hello World - Now With Goals!</title>
  <dc:creator>Tony E. Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://tlint101.github.io/practice-in-code/posts/2-hello-world-goals.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="hello-world---now-with-goals" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hello-world---now-with-goals">Hello World - Now with Goals</h3>
<p>Hello everyone. My name is Tony. I am currently in a Ph.D.&nbsp;program for drug discovery in Taiwan. Why Taiwan? Well, a series of life choices fresh from university led me there. I did not get a start into my field of study overnight. I am a late bloomer. And still learning. Or at least trying to!</p>
<p>I specialize in cheminformatics - using computers to sort and categorize molecules. There’s a lot of good software out there that can help anyone interested into getting into the field. That includes both paid versions, such as <a href="https://www.schrodinger.com/products/maestro">Schrodiner’s Maestro</a>, or open source software such as the wonderful suite available from the <a href="https://www.zbh.uni-hamburg.de/en/forschung/software-server-spgl.html">University of Hamburg</a>. Those tools are great! But I quickly realized that relying on software, as good as they can be, can be very limiting. What if I have an idea that does not fit the available software? What if I want to make modifications to the figures I make? What if I want to try a new screening protocol? There is only one way to do these things - coding! And learning to code requires a lot of practice.</p>
<p>I know that with experience. I have tried learning ot code multiple times in my life. Each time I have failed. There is a whole host of reasons. Maybe the language I chose was not for me. Java, is great, but at the time I can barely wrap my head around it. I tried making a small iOS app in the early days of the iPhone, which used UIKit. No dice. When Apple transitioned into Swift UI, I thought “Great! A new start!” Only to fail horribly.</p>
<p>It was not until I got into the Ph.D.&nbsp;program (and again, I started late!) that I finally tried and… well I did not succeed, but I got way further than before.</p>
<p>What helped was having a project and actually sticking with it. Well, what really helped is that I found a lot of examples online tackling similar problems I had. People writing about their code, sharing new tools and packages, and how to solve them. All of this helped make things simple enough for me to at least get started.</p>
<p>For that, I am forever grateful.</p>
<p><strong>That brings me to this blog. I will use it as a place to practice coding, my thinking and thought processes, what I am interested in, and hopefully, as a way to share with others.</strong></p>
<p>This will be my way of paying it forward.</p>
<p>And barring that, it will be a good place to showcase my failures to the world. I’m ok with that too.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Thoughts</category>
  <guid>https://tlint101.github.io/practice-in-code/posts/2-hello-world-goals.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hello World!</title>
  <dc:creator>Tony E. Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://tlint101.github.io/practice-in-code/posts/1-hello-world.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="hello-world" class="level1">
<h1>Hello World!</h1>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Thoughts</category>
  <guid>https://tlint101.github.io/practice-in-code/posts/1-hello-world.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
